In a No-man's Land between North and South, You didn't fight for the Blue
or the Grey... You fought for your friends and family.
Ride with the Devil is a drama, war, romance film directed by Ang Lee.
Ride with the Devil follows four people who are fighting for truth and
justice amidst the turmoil of the American Civil War.
Director Ang Lee takes us to a no man's land on the Missouri/Kansas border where a staunch loyalist, an immigrant's son, a
freed slave, and a young widow form an unlikely friendship as they learn how to survive in an uncertain time.
In a place without rules and redefine the meaning of bravery and honor.
Jack Bull Chiles, played by Skeet Ulrich.
Jake Roedel, played by Tobey Maguire.
Sue Lee Shelley, played by Jewel.
Daniel Holt, played by Jeffrey Wright.
George Clyde, played by Simon Baker.
Pitt Mackeson, played by Jonathan Rhys Meyers.
Ride with the Devil is a 1999 American revisionist Western film directed by Ang Lee and starring Tobey Maguire, Skeet Ulrich, Jeffrey
Wright, Jewel in her feature film debut, Simon Baker, Jonathan Rhys Meyers, James Caviezel, Thomas Guiry and Jonathan Brandis.
Based on the novel Woe to Live On, by Daniel Woodrell, the film, set during the American Civil War, follows a group of men who join the First Missouri Irregulars, also
known as the Bushwhackers—guerrilla units loyal to pro-Confederacy units of the state—and their war against Northern Jayhawkers allied with the Union army.
The film was a co-production between Universal Studios (the successor
to Polygram Filmed Entertainment) and Good Machine.
Principal photography began on March 25, 1998.
Theatrically, it was commercially distributed by the USA Films division of USA Networks and premiered in only six theaters nationwide in
the United States on November 26, 1999, and for only three days, grossing a total of $635,096 (~$1.12 million in 2024).
Ride with the Devil has been noted for its thematic
exploration of politics, violence and war.
In 2010, The Criterion Collection released a restored high-definition digital transfer for the
home media market, featuring an extended 148-minute director's cut of the film.
The film explores themes of civil war, friends, bush
whacker, raid, american civil war.
The tone is emotional.